Welcome. In the last lecture, we created this anim montage for us to climb to the top. And
欢迎。在上一次讲座中，我们创建了这个动画蒙太奇，让我们爬到顶峰。而
in this lecture, we'll look at how we can use this montage. So the animation is ready.
在这节课中，我们将看看如何使用这个蒙太奇。所以动画已经准备好了。
Now we need to take care of the coding part. I'm gonna close my project. Then I'm gonna
现在我们需要处理一下编码部分。我将关闭我的项目。然后我将
delete these debug functions. So delete this line. And delete these else gates. And inside
删除这些调试函数。所以删除这一行。并删除这些else门。而在
of this function, I'm going to disable the debug shape. So delete this true. And inside
这个函数中，我将禁用调试形状。所以删除这个真。而在
of this trace from iHeight, I'm going to delete this true. We don't need to see any of it
iHeight的跟踪，我将删除这个true。我们不需要看到任何的
now. And I'm going to go back to my header file, scroll down to this climb BP variables.
现在。我将回到我的头文件，向下滚动到这个BP变量。
We'll need another anim montage. So I'm going to copy this one and paste it in here. I'm
我们将需要另一个动画蒙太奇。所以我要复制这个并把它粘贴到这里。我将
going to call this climb to top montage. Then I'm going to go to the CPP file and scroll
我把这个叫做 "爬到顶 "蒙太奇。然后我将进入CPP文件并滚动到
up to the physics climb function. So if this condition is true, I'm going to play the montage.
到物理学的爬升功能。所以如果这个条件是真的，我就会播放这个蒙太奇。
So we can use the function to do so. And passing in climb to top montage. And before I do
所以我们可以用这个函数来做。并传入爬升到顶部蒙太奇。而在我做之前
this, I'm going to first call the function stop climbing. So by doing this, we'll be
之前，我将首先调用函数stop climbing。所以通过这样做，我们将
out of the climbing state and go inside of the falling state. But this still won't work.
出了爬升状态，进入了下降状态。但这仍然不会起作用。
So here we need the montage to lift our character up. But there's one function inside of the
所以在这里我们需要蒙太奇来提升我们的角色。但是在父类中的一个函数
parent class that's preventing us from doing it. So I'm going to go to the header file,
父类中的一个函数使我们无法做到这一点。所以我将进入头文件、
then scroll up. I'm going to select this character moving component, press F12 to go inside of
然后向上滚动。我将选择这个角色移动组件，按F12键，进入它的内部。
it. Then I'm going to search. So the function name is called constrain anim root motion.
它的内部。然后我将进行搜索。所以这个函数的名字叫做约束动画根部运动。
So I'm going to type in constrain and I'm going to search. It's not this one. And this is
所以我将输入constrain，然后我将搜索。这不是这个。而这是
the function that we need to override. If you select this function and you press F12
我们需要覆盖的函数。如果你选择这个函数并按F12
to go inside of it. So you can see in this function, if this is falling is true, then
来进入它的内部。所以你可以看到在这个函数中，如果这个下降是真的，那么
we won't be overriding the velocity that Z. So we won't be able to lift our character
我们将不会覆盖Z的速度。
up if we are inside of the falling state, but that's not what we want. So we'll need
上升，但这不是我们想要的。所以我们需要
to override this. I'm going to select this function again to go to the header file. Then
覆盖这个。我将再次选择这个函数，转到头文件。然后
I'm going to copy this function. So copy it and go back to my header file. I'm going to
我将复制这个函数。所以复制它并回到我的头文件。我将会
paste the function under this get max acceleration and mark this function as override. And I'm
把这个函数粘贴在获得最大加速度下面，并把这个函数标记为重写。然后我
going to create a function definition, place the function under this one. So paste it in
创建一个函数定义，把这个函数放在这个函数下面。所以把它粘贴到
here. Then inside of this function, I'm going to do an if check. So first I'm going to check
这里。然后在这个函数中，我将做一个if检查。所以我首先要检查
if this is falling is true and this owning playerNM instance is true and this owning
如果这个下降是真的，这个拥有的播放器NM实例是真的，这个拥有的
playerNM instance is any montage playing is true. So if these three conditions are all
playerNM实例是任何蒙太奇播放为真。所以如果这三个条件都是
true, then that means we want to override the Z velocity. And for that, I'm going to
为真，那就意味着我们要覆盖Z方向的速度。为此，我将会
create a const local Boolean. I'm going to call this one B is playing I am montage. Then
创建一个常量本地布尔值。我将把这个称为B正在播放我是蒙太奇。然后
I'm going to check. So if this Boolean is true, then I want to return this function
我将进行检查。所以如果这个布尔值是真的，那么我想返回这个函数
input group motion velocity. And if this condition is false, I want to return the super version
输入组运动速度。而如果这个条件是假的，我想返回这个函数的超级版本
of this function. So copy this and paste it in here. Delete the things we don't need.
这个函数的超级版本。所以，复制这个并把它粘贴到这里。删除我们不需要的东西。
And that's pretty much it. I'm going to compile first. Hey, this is me from the future. One
这就差不多了。我先来编译一下。嘿，这就是来自未来的我。有一点
thing to point out here is so I'm going to scroll down to this physics climb. Instead
这里要指出的是，所以我要向下滚动到这个物理学的攀登。而不是
of this function, I'm manually calling stop climbing, but actually we don't need to do
而不是这个函数，我手动调用停止爬升，但实际上我们不需要这样做。
this and calling stop climbing here is way too early. So by playing this climb montage
在这里调用停止爬升是太早了。所以通过播放这个攀爬蒙太奇
here, since we're using it to lift our character up, we'll be transitioning into falling state
就会过渡到下降状态
automatically calling stop climbing before playing this montage will actually cause some
在播放这个蒙太奇之前自动调用停止攀登，实际上会导致一些
issues later. You'll see what that is very soon. Even though we don't need this function
以后的问题。你很快就会看到那是什么。尽管我们不需要这个函数
stop climbing, since we will be transitioning into the falling state automatically, we'll
停止爬升，因为我们将自动过渡到下降状态，我们仍然需要保留这个函数。
still need to keep the function. Constraint and then root motion velocity in order to
仍然需要保留这个函数。约束，然后是根部运动的速度，以便
allow our root motion to lift our character up. Alright, back to the Omi. And I have a
让我们的根部运动将我们的角色抬起来。好了，回到欧米的问题上。我有一个
successful compile. And the last thing that I want to do, so I'm going to go down to this
编译成功。我想做的最后一件事是，我要去看一下这个
own climb montage ended and I'm going to add an L skates. So in the L skates, I'm going
自己的攀登蒙太奇结束，我要添加一个L型溜冰鞋。所以在L型溜冰鞋中，我将会
to directly set the movement mode here to move walk. So once we are downplaying climb
直接将运动模式设置为移动行走。所以，一旦我们把爬升
to top montage, we should be entering this walking mode. Alright, I'm going to launch
到顶部的蒙太奇，我们就应该进入这个步行模式。好的，我将启动
my editor back and go inside of my editor. I'm going to duplicate a new mesh. So select
我的编辑器，然后进入我的编辑器内部。我将复制一个新的网格。所以选择
this mesh, press out on my keyboard, duplicate it, drag it to here. Then I'm going to delete
这个网格，按键盘上的键，复制它，把它拖到这里。然后我将删除
this player start. Now when we press play, we should be able to start at the camera position.
这个播放器开始。现在，当我们按下播放键时，我们应该能够从摄像机的位置开始。
Then I'm going to go into this climb system, open this BPE climb character. Inside of the
然后我将进入这个攀爬系统，打开这个BPE攀爬角色。在这个
movement component, I'm going to assign the montage in here. Then click compile and I'm
运动组件中，我将把蒙太奇分配到这里。然后点击编译，我将
going to test. So press play, go to the surface, enter the climb state, then try to climb up.
进行测试。所以按下播放键，到表面去，进入攀爬状态，然后试着爬上去。
And there you go. The montage is working. It's just that the play rate is not high enough.
然后你就可以了。蒙太奇正在工作。只是播放率还不够高。
I'm going to increase the play rate of it. So go inside of this climb to top, I'm going
我打算提高它的播放率。所以在这个爬到顶的过程中，我将
to increase its race scale to 2.1. Click save, then click play and go to the surface, climb
把它的比赛规模增加到2.1。点击保存，然后点击播放，去到表面，爬上
to the top. Alright, it's looking much better. I'm going to try it with this surface. So
到顶部。好了，现在看起来好多了。我打算用这个表面来试试。所以
climb to the top. And I noticed a small issue. So when we get to the top, the feet of our
爬到顶部。我注意到一个小问题。所以当我们爬到顶部时，我们的角色的脚
character are clipping through the ground. And to fix that, we can go back to our sequencer.
角色的脚在地面上被削掉了。为了解决这个问题，我们可以回到我们的序列器中。
So go to the content folder, double click to open this anim map, click save, select it,
所以到内容文件夹，双击打开这个动画地图，点击保存，选择它、
and go to this animation folder, raw, climb to the top, double click to open this sequencer
然后到这个动画文件夹中，生，爬到顶部，双击打开这个序列器
and select this route control. So to fix that issue, at the first frame, I'm going to lower
并选择这个路线控制。所以为了解决这个问题，在第一帧，我将把根部的骨头降低一点
the root bone down a little bit, then click this add key. Then I'm going to move to the
根部的骨头降低一点，然后点击这个添加键。然后我将移动到
final frame and push this root bone down a little bit to somewhere near here. Then click
最后一帧，把这个根骨往下推一点，推到靠近这里的地方。然后点击
this add key. Alright, I'm going to click this button here to sync the changes. And
这个添加键。好的，我将点击这个按钮来同步这些变化。然后
I'm going to preview the changes that we've made. So go back to this montages folder,
我将预览我们所做的改变。所以回到这个蒙太奇文件夹、
open this anim montage and click pause in here. So you can see when we reach to the
打开这个动画蒙太奇，点击这里的暂停。所以你可以看到当我们到了
final frame, our feet are on the ground. I'm going to click save, then I'm going to go
最后一帧时，我们的脚已经在地上了。我将点击保存，然后我将去
back to my third person map. So open this maps, double click to open it, click save,
回到我的第三人称地图。所以打开这个地图，双击打开它，点击保存、
select it, then I'm going to try again. So click play, start climbing, move to the top,
选择它，然后我再试一次。所以点击播放，开始爬升，移动到顶部、
and just like that. It's working as expected. How beautiful is that? And there's another
就像这样。它像预期的那样工作了。这多漂亮啊？还有一个
issue that I noticed. So if I hold down W key the whole time and press F, I won't be
我注意到另一个问题。所以，如果我一直按住W键，然后按F键，我将无法
able to enter the climb state. And the reason for that is I think I made a mistake in the
能进入爬升状态。其原因是我认为我在代码中犯了一个错误。
code. So I'm going to go back to my code. Inside of this check has reached the ledge.
代码。所以我要回到我的代码中去。在这个检查里面已经到达了壁架。
So we don't actually need to call the function start climbing. I'm going to delete this line.
所以我们实际上不需要调用开始爬升这个函数。我将删除这一行。
When the condition is true, if we call it start climbing, then we'll leave the climb
当条件为真时，如果我们调用它开始爬升，那么我们就会离开爬升
state and if I hold down my W key the whole time, my ground speed will be greater than
状态，如果我一直按住W键，我的地面速度将大于
zero. Then we'll be transitioning into the for loop state and that's not what we want.
零。然后我们就会过渡到for loop状态，这不是我们想要的。
At the end of this montage, we've already set the movement mode to the walking mode.
在这个蒙太奇的最后，我们已经将运动模式设置为行走模式。
So this way it should work just fine. All right, I'm going to quickly save all then
所以这样应该可以正常工作了。好的，我将快速保存所有然后
trigger left coding. All right, left coding succeeded. I'm going to test again. So hold
触发左键编码。好的，左键编码成功了。我要再次测试。所以请按住
down W key the whole time. Yeah, this way is working much better. So we can enter the
一直按住W键。是的，这种方式工作得更好。所以我们可以进入
climb state then climb up the ledge. If we don't want to do that, we'll be entering the
攀爬状态，然后爬上壁架。如果我们不想这样做，我们将进入空闲状态，然后爬上壁架。
idle state then climb up the ledge. And that's great. Everything is working as expected.
闲置状态，然后爬上壁架。而这很好。一切都在按预期工作。
Later, when you try to implement this by yourself, so first you'll need to play the montage,
以后，当你试图自己实现这个时，那么首先你需要播放蒙太奇、
then don't forget to override the root motion constraint. And if your feet like mine are
然后别忘了覆盖根部运动约束。如果你的脚像我一样是
clipping through the ground, you can fix that by adjusting the root control and don't forget
你可以通过调整根部控制来解决这个问题。
to set your movement mode back to walking when your montage has ended. All right, it's
当你的蒙太奇结束时，把你的运动模式设置为步行。好了，现在是
time for you to do the same. I'll see you in the next lecture.
是时候让你做同样的事情了。我们在下一个讲座中再见吧。
[Music]
[音乐]